Darren Tan

Software Engineer

+65 9106 1430 Singaporean

darrentan.yf@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuanfengdarren/

SUMMARY

My experience as a Business Manager has given me the edge as a developer with unique insights on the Business Development domain. With a client-centric mindset, it has enabled me as a developer to customise my approach to a problem and identify specific strategies for every client.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: JavaScript, React, Express, Node.js, HTML/CSS, jQuery, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, TDD, Cypress, Python

EXPERIENCE

AVIQ (S) PTE LTD, Singapore - Business Manager

JANUARY 2014 - AUGUST 2021

- Sales & Business Development
 - Managed technical presentations of products for prospective clients, partners and resellers
 - Engaged with clients to understand their needs and developed customized solutions to their requirements
 - Developed business through networking for potential referrals and collaboration from various industries

Website

- Reviewed company's website analytics to assess behaviour of visitors and implemented changes to improve visitor retention
- Overhaul of <u>company's website</u> using Wordpress to improve design, content and optimize product placement

Accomplishments

- Increased yearly local sales by 27% in 2018, 29% in 2019 and 41% in 2020 (1st Quarter)
- Improved labour efficiency by a 75% decrease in time taken for goods intake, from 2 hours to 30 minutes
- Clinched multiple government projects and established a strong footing in the investment and medical sectors

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

General Assembly, Singapore - Software Engineer Immersive

SEPTEMBER 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

- Find My Carpark
 - Web-based application to search for the location of shopping malls and their respective parking rates
 - o Build in React, Node.js with Google Maps API
- GroupBuy
 - Web-based application as an alternative platform to allow individuals to organize or join group buys instead of using Facebook Groups or Google Docs
 - o Built in React, Express, Node.js and MongoDB
- Hands On
 - Web-based application that allows individuals to create and share DIY guides, with features to include feedback and ratings
 - Build in React, Express, Node.js PostgreSQL and Cypress for Testing

EDUCATION

University of London, Singapore - Bachelors in Economics and Finance 2014 - 2018

Singapore Polytechnic, Singapore - Diploma in Banking and Finance 2009 - 2012

TRAINING

Tableau, Singapore - Desktop Specialist Certification 2021

Google, Singapore - Associate Engineer Certification 2020

General Assembly, Singapore - UX Design Course 2019

AVAILABILITY

1 Month's Notice